Gratitude is more than just saying ‘thank you’ to someone who has helped us or given us a gift.
感恩绝不仅仅是对帮助过我们或赠予我们礼物的人说一句“谢谢”。
Gratitude is a deeper appreciation for someone or something that makes us feel a positive emotion.
感恩是对某个人或某件事物更深层次的感谢，这种欣赏能让我们产生积极的情绪。
And this positive emotion can be good for our health – our emotional and physical health, as well as the health of our relationships.
而这种积极情绪有益于我们的健康——无论是情绪健康、身体健康，还是人际关系的“健康”。
Let’s start by looking at the emotional or mental health benefits of expressing gratitude.
我们先来看表达感恩对情绪健康或心理健康的益处。
There have been many studies, as described in a 2018 paper from the Greater Good Science Center titled ‘The Science of Gratitude’, showing that writing a gratitude letter to another person or writing in a gratitude journal, if done regularly, improves mental health.
加州大学伯克利分校“至善科学中心”2018年发表了一篇题为《感恩的科学》的论文，其中提及的多项研究表明，定期给他人写感恩信或撰写感恩日记，能改善心理健康。
One reason for this, is that gratitude stops us from ruminating on toxic, negative emotions, and writing a ‘thank you’ letter, for example, shifts our attention so that we focus on positive emotions.
其中一个原因是，感恩能让我们不再沉湎于有害的负面情绪，比如写一封感谢信，就能转移我们的注意力，让我们聚焦于积极情绪。
But even if we don’t share our writing with anyone, like in a journal, the act of completing the exercise alone makes us happier and more satisfied with life.
即便我们不把写好的内容分享给任何人（比如写在私人日记里），单是完成这项书写练习的过程，就能让我们更快乐，对生活更满意。
And this gets better with time.
而且这种积极效果会随着时间推移愈发显著。
As we are essentially training our brain to be more in tune with noticing the positive, after several weeks or months, this becomes more intuitive.
本质上，我们是在训练大脑更敏锐地捕捉生活中的积极事物，几周或几个月之后，这种能力会变得更加本能。
And so, the more we express gratitude, the more positive we feel.
因此，我们表达感恩的次数越多，内心的积极感受就会越强烈。
Gratitude can also make us feel good in our bodies.
感恩同样能让我们的身体感到舒畅。
There are studies linking a gratitude practice to better sleep quality, better eating habits, and reduced inflammation in people who have had heart problems.
有研究表明，坚持践行感恩之举，能改善睡眠质量、养成更健康的饮食习惯，还能减轻心脏病患者体内的炎症反应。
So gratitude is clearly good for us, but is it also good for the people in our lives?
由此可见，感恩对我们自身益处良多，但它对我们身边的人是否也有积极影响呢？
The simple answer is ‘yes’.
答案很简单——“是的”。
When shared – spoken or written – gratitude is about feeling valued and helping others feel valued too.
当感恩以口头或书面的形式传递出去时，我们自身能体会到被重视的感觉，同时也帮助他人感受到被珍视。
Feeling valued can help build stronger relationships – be it with family, partners, friends or even colleagues.
感受到被重视有助于维系更牢固的人际关系——无论是与家人、伴侣、朋友，还是与同事之间的关系。
And that’s on top of all the other ways gratitude is clearly good for us.
这是除了感恩对我们自身的种种益处之外，又一个值得我们坚持践行的理由。
Maybe we should all stop counting sheep or counting calories and start counting our blessings instead?
或许我们都该停止数羊助眠或计算卡路里，转而开始细数生活中的幸事？